Guide to the Radio TV Services Records, circa 1937 - 2008
Duke University. University Archives
Radio TV Services records circa 1937 - 2008
Duke University. Radio TV Services.
36.5 linear feet, Extent: 7100 Items
Duke University. University Archives
Established in 1954 as part of the Office of Information Services (now the Office of News and Communications,) Radio TV Services supervises the production of materials for radio and television, assists in the preparation of audio-visual materials needed by the university, and promotes the University's exposure to local, state, and national audiences. It makes documentary films, covers events and functions on campus, sets up news conferences in cooperation with local and national media, interviews university personnel, and provides features on students for their home-town media. Collection includes correspondence, subject files, sound recordings (audiocassettes and reel-to-reel tapes), film (16mm), and video tape (U-Matic and 2-inch quadruplex). Notable people documented on film and tape include Keith Brodie, Terry Sanford, Douglas M. Knight, Orin Pilkey, Robert Menzies, Jerry Falwell, Billy Graham, Queen Noor al Hussein, Jesse Jackson, Waylon Jennings, Juanita Kreps, Robert McNamara, Ronald Reagan, William Westmoreland, Desmond Tutu, Elie Wiesel, Reynolds Price, Martin Luther King, Jr., Hubert Humphrey, Richard Nixon, Stokely Carmichael, Kenneth Clark, Sidney Cohen, Adam Clayton Powell, Betty Friedan, B. F. Skinner, Sam Ervin, Alex Haley, Tom Wolfe, Buckminster Fuller, and Cesar Chavez. Subjects include Duke University basketball, football, commencement, convocation, homecoming, the Epoch Campaign announcement, student unrest in the 60s, the Silent Vigil held after the death of Dr. King, the Duke Marine Laboratory, the discovery of the U.S.S. Monitor, oceanographic research, the 1954 Orange Bowl, Joe College Weekend, various campus scenes, Duke Gardens, and the Richard Nixon Library controversy. Completed films include Response to Our Challenge and This is Duke. English.
RL.01807
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Use of audiotapes, films, and videotapes from this collection requires the creation of reference copies. Reference copies for a few of the films have been made on VHS and DVD, and if a reference copy exists, it is noted in this finding aid. To arrange for the creation of reference copies of other items, please contact University Archives staff. Although these recordings and films are now stored in a stable environment, their condition and playback quality is unknown.
Provenance
The Radio TV Services Records was received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1988; 2008, accession numbers UA88-57, UA2008-0048, UA2008-0065.
Historical Note
Established in 1954 as part of the Office of Information Services (now the Office of News and Communications,) Radio TV Services supervises the production of materials for radio and television, assists in the preparation of audio-visual materials needed by the university, and promotes the University's exposure to local, state, and national audiences. Harry Durham was the director from 1964-1966, followed by Charlie Braswell, who held the position until 1988.
The office produced a daily news program, The News of Duke, and a weekly radio program, Challenges in Education (which eventually aired on more than 100 stations, including Voice of America and the Armed Forces Network). It also made documentary films, such as Medicine at the Crossroads (1966). It covers events and functions on campus, including trustee meetings, convocations, and protests. It sets up news conferences in cooperation with local and national media, interviews university personnel, and provides features on students for their home-town media.
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, subject files, sound recordings (audiocassettes and reel-to-reel tapes), film (16mm), and video tape (U-Matic and 2-inch quadruplex)of events related to Duke occurring both on and off campus. There is a detailed subject file on index cards for most of the film and some of the sound recordings, as well as other indexes and notes.
Notable people documented on film and tape include Keith Brodie, Terry Sanford, Douglas M. Knight, Orin Pilkey, Robert Menzies, Jerry Falwell, Billy Graham, Queen Noor al Hussein, Jesse Jackson, Waylon Jennings, Juanita Kreps, Robert McNamara, Ronald Reagan, William Westmoreland, Desmond Tutu, Elie Wiesel, Reynolds Price, Martin Luther King, Jr., Hubert Humphrey, Richard Nixon, Stokely Carmichael, Kenneth Clark, Sidney Cohen, Adam Clayton Powell, Betty Friedan, B. F. Skinner, Sam Ervin, Alex Haley, Tom Wolfe, Buckminster Fuller, and Cesar Chavez. There are also film and recordings documenting Duke University basketball, football, commencement, convocation, homecoming, the Epoch Campaign announcement, student unrest in the 60s, the Silent Vigil held after the death of Dr. King, the Duke Marine Laboratory, the discovery of the U.S.S. Monitor, oceanographic research, the 1954 Orange Bowl, Joe College Weekend, various campus scenes, Duke Gardens, and the Richard Nixon Library controversy. Completed films include Response to Our Challenge and This is Duke.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be accessed under the following subject headings in the Duke University Libraries online catalog.
Brodie, H. Keith H. (Harlow Keith Hammond), 1939-; Duke University -- Basketball -- History.; Duke University -- Football -- History; Duke University -- History -- 20th century.; Duke University -- Joe College Weekend; Duke University. Marine Laboratory -- History; Duke University. Radio TV Services; Duke University -- Students.; King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968; Knight, Douglas M., 1921-; Menzies, Robert J. (Robert James), 1923-1976.; Monitor (Ironclad); Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-; Pilkey, Orrin H., 1934-; Price, Reynolds, 1933-; Sanford, Terry, 1917-; Motion pictures; Sound recordings
Contents of Collection
- General Correspondence C-Z, 1964-1973
  Correspondence files of Harry Durham and Charlie Braswell, directors of Radio TV Services. The A and B folders are missing.
  - Correspondence C-Z (Box 1)
- Subject folders, 1954-1986
  Correspondence, reports, minutes, memoranda, and other materials concerning the campus radio and TV stations, the introduction of FM broadcasting, public relations, film projects, and other activities.
  - Subject Folders A-M (Box 1)
  - Subject Folders N-Z (Box 2)
- Indexes and Notes, 1956-1974 and undated
  - Card File Index (Box 3)
    Extensive subject, and numerical index created by the department. Materials indexed are reel to reel audiotapes (numbered B-1 through B-773), 16mm films (numbered C-1 through C-164 and D-1 through D-8), and scripts (which are not part of the existing collection.) Audio cassettes, some of the 16mm films, and videotapes are not included in the index.
  - C-Series Films: Notes for Subject Index, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - C-Series Films: Title Index, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Continuity: Duke Founder's Day Film (Duke 140), Dec. 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Original elements for Duke 140 are in Box 17 and Box 20. Audiotape is in Box 12.
  - D2 and D3: List of Shots, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Typed list of shots for Film D-2 and a handwritten list of shots for Films D-2 and D-3 of Terry Sanford's inauguration. Film D-2 is in Box 15. Film D-3 is missing from the collection.
  - Epoch Campaign Script, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Full title of the script is For Humankind and History: A Time for Greatness at Duke. Film related to the Epoch Campaign is in Box 15 and Box 20. Audiotape of the Epoch Campaign Announcement is in Box 11.
  - Description of Film from the Music Building Dedication, Nov. 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Two-page typewritten list of shots. This film does not exist in the collection.
  - Description of Films (Numbered Series), Nov. 2, 1971, and undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Handwritten and typed list of shots for some of the films in the Numbered Series in Box 15.
  - Letter Re: Quest Without End, Mar. 1, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Quest Without End was a color sound film about Duke University. A copy of the film and its original elements are in Box 18.
  - Mimeographs: Football Games, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    Mimeographed shot lists for two of the films in Box 18: Duke vs. N.C. State and Duke vs. South Carolina.
  - News Conference: U.S.S. Monitor, Mar. 7, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Folder containing press releases, correspondence, black and white photographs, and other printed materials.
  - This is Duke, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    A typed description of the film This is Duke plus a xerox copy of an article about the film from the Alumni Register, Sept. 1954.
  - C-160 Shot List, Apr. 28, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    A handwritten list of shots from film #C-160, Presentation Ceremony of some type at Duke Homestead.
  - Cenntennial Year, 1938-1939, Initial Appraisal, Apr. 17, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Sound Recordings, 1960-1988 and undated
  In addition to individuals related to Duke such as Keith Brodie, Terry Sanford, and Douglas M. Knight, a number of other notable people are represented in the sound recordings: Jerry Falwell, Billy Graham, Queen Noor al Hussein, Jesse Jackson, Waylon Jennings, Juanita Kreps, Robert McNamara, Ronald Reagan, William Westmoreland, Desmond Tutu, Elie Wiesel, Reynolds Price, Martin Luther King, Jr., Hubert Humphrey, Richard Nixon, Stokely Carmichael, Kenneth Clark, Sidney Cohen, Adam Clayton Powell, Betty Friedan, B. F. Skinner, Sam Ervin, Alex Haley, Tom Wolfe, Buckminster Fuller, and Cesar Chavez. There are also tapes pertinent to Duke University basketball, commencement, student unrest in the 60s, the Silent Vigil held after the death of Dr. King, the discovery of the U.S.S. Monitor, and oceanographic research.
  Original recordings are closed to use. Digitized access copies are available for some recordings. Please contact University Archives staff for more information.
  - Cassettes, 1970-1988, undated
    Arranged in the original alphabetical order in which they were received.
    - AT&T gift to Duke. News Conference, Oct. 14, 1985 (Box 4, Cassette box 4A)
    - American Dance Festival. News Conference, circa 1978
    - American Musical Theatre. News Conference, Sept. 23, 1977
    - Manny Azenberg meets press, undated
    - Basketball Team returns from Final Four. Event, Apr. 2, 1986
    - Basketball Team returns from Final Four in Kansas City. Event, Apr. 15, 1986
    - Dr. Brodie. First talk to Academic Council. Address, Sept. 26, 1985
    - Brodie. Inauguration, Sept. 28, 1985
    - Brodie, undated
    - Dr. Keith Brodie named President of Duke. News Conference, Dec. 4, 1984
    - Dr. Brodie's first public talk. Welcome Freshmen. Address, Aug. 21, 1985
    - Bryan Center. Dedication, Feb. 26, 1982
    - Bryan Research Building Groundbreaking, Feb. 12, 1986
    - Dr. Z. Brzezinski, Former National Security Advisor to President Carter. News Conference, Dec. 9, 1987
    - Carol Burnett. News Conference, Apr. 10, 1985
    - Campaign for Arts & Sciences, $200 million. News Conference, Dec. 4, 1984
    - CAMA. Tapes 1-5, undated
    - A.Calero. Contra. News Conference, 1986
    - A.Calero (Contra) to students. Page Auditorium, 1986
    - Chronicle. 75th Anniversary. 2 Tapes, Nov. 14, 1980
    - 5 Years of Coastal Zone Management. Media Briefing. Tapes 6, 7 of 7, Mar. 29, 1980-Mar. 30, 1980
    - Commencement: Heard, 1975
    - Commencement: Sanford, 1976
    - Commencement: Kreps, 1977
    - Commencement. Tape 2 only, 1978 (Box 4, Cassette box 4B)
    - Commencement. Tapes 1 and 2, 1979
    - Commencement. Tape 1 only, 1980
    - Commencement. Tapes 1 and 2, 1981
    - Commencement. Tapes 1 and 2, 1982
    - Commencement. Tapes 1 and 2, 1983
    - Commencement. Tape 1 only, 1984
    - Commencement. Tapes 1 and 2, 1985
    - Commencement, 1986
    - Commencement: Ted Koppel, 1987
    - Commencement: Garry Trudeau, 1988
    - Duke North (Hospital): plans to open. News Conference, Jan. 14, 1980
    - 50th Anniversary of Duke. Symposium. 5 tapes, Apr. 11, 1980-Apr. 12, 1980
    - C. A. Dukes. Talks regarding 1938 film on Duke University, undated
    - Dr. R. Eisenson, DUMC. News Conference, Mar. 5, 1987
    - Reverend Jerry Falwell. News Conference, undated
    - For Humankind and History, Sept. 1975
    - For Humankind and History. 2 Tapes, Sept. 1976
    - Founder's Days Convocation, Dec. 11, 1986
    - Founder's Days Convocation, Dec. 10, 1987
    - Fuqua, $4 million gift from R. David Thomas (Wendy's). News Conference, June 13, 1986 (Box 4, Cassette box 4C)
    - Fuqua Business School. Dedication, Apr. 1983
    - J. B. Fuqua. News Conference, undated
    - Fuqua School of Business. Groundbreaking, Feb. 18, 1981
    - Pamela Gann, New Law Dean Introduced, May 9, 1988
    - Dr. Billy Graham. News Conference, Nov. 19, 1985
    - Former Senator Gary Hart. Major Speaker Series, Jan. 27, 1987
    - Hemo Sponge, Dr. Bonaventura, Marine Lab. News Conference, undated
    - Queen Noor Al Hussein. Address, Apr. 16, 1985
    - Hyperbonic Chamber, 1981
    - Jesse Jackson. Tapes 1 and 2, undated
    - Waylon Jennings. News Conference, Sept. 9, 1987
    - Surgeon General Koop. News Conference, Feb. 1986
    - J. Kreps, Secretary of Commerce. Address, May 8, 1977
    - J. Kreps, Secretary of Commerce. Address, Oct. 19, 1977
    - Ann Landers. News Conference, Feb. 12, 1986
    - Arthur Larson. International Law, Sept. 1970
    - Jack Lemmon, Jonathan Miller. Play. News Conference, Mar. 10, 1986
    - Robert McNamara. News Conference, Oct. 15, 1986
    - Moroccan Ambassador. News Conference, Sept. 13, 1985
    - Nixon Library. Alex McMahon, Chairman of the Board. News Conference, Sept. 14, 1981
    - Nixon Library. Alex McMahon, Chairman of the Board. News Conference, Sept. 4, 1981
    - Nixon Library. Alex McMahon, Chairman of the Board. News Conference, Oct. 6, 1981
    - Dr. William O'Barr. ABC Radio, Feb. 6, 1985
    - Earl Owensby, movies. News Conference, Jan. 30, 1986
    - Dr. Chris Quigg, Dr. Goshaw: Super Conducting Super Collider. News Conference, undated
    - President Ronald Reagan at Duke. Substance Abuse. (2 Copies), Feb. 8, 1988
    - Regional sports arena. Discussion, Apr. 2, 1979
    - Terry Sanford. News Conference, Jan. 13, 1976 (Box 4, Cassette box 4D)
    - Terry Sanford to Duke Faculty. Address, Sept. 25, 1975
    - Terry Sanford to 1976 CASE. Address, 1976
    - Sanford Returns to Duke, Jan. 26, 1976
    - President Sanford to Faculty Meeting, Oct. 30, 1980
    - President Sanford to Alumni. Final Talk, June 8, 1985
    - D. Seaver and T. Sanford, Dec. 1974
    - Shevchensko, Former Soviet Ambassador to U.N. News Conference, Apr. 1987
    - Neil Simon and Gene Saks. Broadway Bound. News Conference, Oct. 3, 1986
    - Eleanor Smeal, President of NOW. News Conference, 1986
    - John Spencer: Last Leonardo da Vinci Found. News Conference, circa 1979-1980
    - Dr. Stern of Burroughs Corporation. News Conference, 1986
    - Teer Engineering Library. Dedication, Sept. 7, 1984
    - Thelonius Monk Institute of Jazz. News Conference, June 20, 1988
    - Bishop Tutu in Duke Chapel. Address, Jan. 19, 1986
    - Bill van Alstya to VOA, undated
    - Video History Archive. Dedication, Nov. 21, 1986
    - Alvin Weingerg, Nuclear Energy. News Conference, Mar. 14, 1986
    - General William Westmoreland. Address, Sept. 19, 1985
    - Elie Wiesel. Major Speakers, Sept. 15, 1987
    - Mr. Wyman, CBS Board Chairman. Address, Feb. 5, 1985
    - Mr. Wyman, CBS Board Chairman. News Conference, Feb. 5, 1985
    - Unknown, undated
    - Unknown, undated
  - Reel-to-Reel Tapes, 1960-1975, undated
    All audiotapes in this series are 1/4 inch tape on open reels. Reels are 7 inch except where noted. This series is indexed by title and by subject in the card file index in Box 3.
    Reel-to-reel audiotapes were originally numbered B-1 through B-773. That arrangement has been retained here. Approximately twenty un-numbered tapes are listed at the end of the series in the same order in which they were received.
    - Submillimeter Waves, Dr. Walter Gordy, April 14, 1964 (Box 5, Reel B-3)
    - Interview with Dr. Knight and Charlie Harville, ACC Sportscaster, undated (Reel B-5)
    - Dr. Knight. Interview by Mr. Clarence Whitfield, March, 1964 (Reel B-10)
    - Oceanography: Eastward Launching, Sturgeon Bay, Wisconsin, May 9, 1964 (Reel B-16)
    - Duke Ambassadors, Jan. 10, 1960 (Reel B-19)
    - Day: Mr. George V. Allen - main address, WDBS radio recording, 1961 (Reel B-20)
    - Dr. Knight's 1st Press Conference as President, Sept. 3, 1963 (Reel B-21)
    - Knight's Inauguration Dinner, Dec. 10, 1963 (Reel B-22)
    - Commencement Address: Dr. Merrimon Cunningham, Board of Trustees, 1963 (Reel B-23)
    - Graduation Speech, undated (Reel B-24)
    - Commencement: Dr. Calvin B. Hooper, Dr. Douglas Knight, June 1, 1964 (Reel B-30)
    - Dr. Arthur Larson, June 11, 1964 (Reel B-39)
    - News Conference: Phytotron Announcement, June 29, 1964, 1 sound reel: 5 inch, 1/4 inch. (Reel B-44)
    - Library: Dan McGrath, Curator, Rare Books Room, July 22, 1964 (Reel B-47)
    - Oceanography: Dr. Menzies on oceanographic research, undated (Reel B-49)
    - R. T. Cole: J. B. Duke Profs, undated July 22, 1964 (Reel B-76)
    - Founder's Day: Dr. Knight's Speech, Dec. 10, 1962 (Reel B-83-1)
    - Founder's Day: Dr. Knight's Speech, Dec. 10, 1962 (Reel B-83-2)
    - Founder's Day: Dr. Knight's Speech, Dec. 10, 1962 (Reel B-83-3)
    - Commonwealth Interview, Commonwealth Studies Center: Dr. Robert Wilson Dec. 10, 1962 (Reel B-85)
    - Convocation: Dr. Knight's Speech, Sept. 24, 1964 (Reel B-97)
    - Alumni Affairs Interview: Mr. Roger Marshall, Nov. 1964 (Reel B-106)
    - Interview on Food Service: Mr. Ted Minah, Oct. 1, 1964 (Reel B-107)
    - Writing: Interview with Mr. Reynolds Price, Oct. 2, 1964 (Reel B-108)
    - Remarks concerning Phytotron: Dr. Paul Kramer, Oct. 1964, 1 sound reel: 5 inch, 1/4 inch. (Reel B-110)
    - Writing: Interview with Mr. Reynolds Price, Oct. 1964 (Reel B-111)
    - Oceanography: Interviews, Dr. Robert J. Menzies, Captain Beveridge on Eastward, Nov. 20, 1964 (Reel B-129)
    - Mr. Wright Tisdale, Chairman of Board of Trustees, speaking at Duke Law School, Nov. 13, 1964 (Reel B-133)
    - Student Activity: Telephone interview with Mr. Bob Newhart, Oct. 1964 (Reel B-140)
    - Oceanography: Eastward Sound Effects for the Bridge, Nov. 20, 1964 (Reel B-143)
    - College Finances: Interview with Mr. C. G. Henricks, Nov. 1964 (Reel B-147)
    - Miss Heather Low, Pres, Women's Student Government, Feb. 9, 1965 (Reel B-190)
    - Interview with Dr. Charles Vail on Engineering Week, Feb. 1965 (Reel B-201)
    - Interview: Mr. Winston Broadfoot on George Washington Flowers Collec., Feb. 22, 1965 (Reel B-203)
    - The South in Continuity and Change Symposium: Dr. Knight, Dr. Thompson, Feb. 21, 1965 (Reel B-216-A)
    - The South in Continuity and Change Symposium: Dr. Knight, Dr. Thompson, Feb. 21, 1965 (Reel B-216-B)
    - Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.: Student Union Speaker Series, Nov. 64 (Box 6, Reel B-224-A)
      Another recording of Dr. King's speech is in the collection: WDBS Collection, 1949-1983. An audiocassette reference copy of this recording has been made.
      There are two unnumbered tapes in Box 12 of this collection entitled King #1 and King #2. Presumably, these tapes are also recordings of Dr. King's speech.
    - Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.: Student Union Speaker Series, Nov. 64 (Reel B-224-B)
    - Dr. Knight's Announcement on the 10 year program, Mar. 9, 1965 (Reel B-225)
    - Interview: Dr. Kenneth Clark on Greek New Testament Project, Mar. 1965 (Reel B-234)
    - Prof. William Blackburn reading poetry, Apr. 1965 (Reel B-242)
    - Interview with Prof. Iain Hamilton on composing, Apr. 15, 1965 (Reel B-248)
    - Student Union Major Speaker: General Lewis B. Hershey, Feb. 13, 1965 (Reel B-250)
    - Oceanography: Interview with Dr. Robert Menzies, Apr. 21, 1965 (Reel B-251)
    - Oceanography: Interview with Dr. C. G. Brookhout onboard the "Eastward", Apr. 20, 1965 (Reel B-252)
    - Vice President Humphrey's Address: Duke University Indoor Stadium, Apr. 24, 1965. (Reel B-253-A)
      A CD reference copy of this recording has been made. Data file masters also exist for this recording.Enter scope/content note.
    - Vice President Humphrey's Address: Duke University Indoor Stadium, Apr. 24, 1965. (Reel B-253-B)
      - A CD reference copy of this recording has been made. Data file masters also exist for this recording.
    - H. Humphrey, 1965 (Reel B-253-A)
    - H. Humphrey, 1965 (Reel B-253-B)
    - Oceanography: Eastward Dedication Luncheon, Morehead City, N.C., May 1, 1965 (Reel B-260)
    - Oceanography: Eastward Dedication Dock Ceremonies, May 1, 1965 (Reel B-261-A)
    - Oceanography: Eastward Dedication Dock Ceremonies, May 1, 1965 (Reel B-261-B)
    - Interview: Dr. Marcus E. Hobbs on the Research Triangle Institute, undated (Reel B-263)
    - Education: Interview with Miss Fannie Mitchell on Job Placement, May 25, 1965 (Reel B-273)
    - Study of American States: Interview: Former N.C. Governor Terry Sanford, Quail Roost, Mar. 28, 1965 (Reel B-274)
    - Graduation Exercises: Gr. Gordon N. Ray, Pres. John Simon Gughenheim Fndtn.: "The Arts and Humanities", June 7, 1965 (Reel B-281)
    - Dr. Douglas Knight: Address at UNC Commencement, June 7, 1965 (Reel B-282)
    - Interview with Mr. Anton Brees, Carillon Recital, June 6, 1965 (Reel B-286)
    - Duke Chapel Carillon Feature for WPTF Kaleidoscope: Mr. Anton Brees, June 1965 (Reel B-301)
    - Economics: Interview with Dr. Calvin Hoover, June 1965 (Reel B-302-A)
    - Parapsychology: Interview with Dr. J. B. Rhine, Aug. 1965 (Reel B-323)
    - Duke Chapel Carillon, Aug. 7, 1965 (Reel B-324)
    - Interview with Dean E. R. Latty, Sept. 13, 1965 (Reel B-331)
    - Duke Convocation: Dr. D. M. Knight, Mr. G. Allen, Sept. 23, 1965 (Reel B-339)
    - Library Ground-breaking, Sept. 23, 1965 (Reel B-340)
    - Interview and sound effects: Mr. Giorgio Ciompi on the violin, Oct. 1, 1965 (Reel B-344)
    - Sound effects: Duke Chapel Carillon, Chapel Organ, Classroom sounds, undated (Reel B-349)
    - Interview: Dean Margaret Ball on Education and Women, Oct. 26, 1965 (Reel B-356)
    - Dr. Knight's Speech to Erasmus Club: The Longest Journey, Nov. 1, 1965 (Reel B-360)
    - Congressman C. Weltner's Speech at Duke Law School, Nov. 8, 1965, 1 sound reel: 5 inch, 1/4 inch. (Reel B-364)
    - Reverend Read: Who's God is Dead, Nov. 14, 1965 (Reel B-371)
    - Interview: Dr. Henry Newson on the Van de Graph [Van de Graaff] Accelerator, Dec. 1965 (Reel B-374)
    - Physics: Press Conference on Nuclear Structure Lab, Nov. 23, 1965 (Box 7, Reel B-377)
    - Narration from Duke Univ. Movie, Response to our Challenge, Dec. 1965 (Reel B-379)
    - Dr. Thomas J. J. Altizer Speech in Duke Chapel, God is Dead, Nov. 9, 1965 (Reel B-385)
    - International Rule of Law in Propaganda Conference, Feb. 18, 1966 (Reel B-431-A)
    - International Rule of Law in Propaganda Conference, Feb. 18, 1966 (Reel B-431-B)
    - Discussion at International Rule of Law in Propaganda Conference, Feb. 22, 1966 (Reel B-431-C)
    - Interview: Dr. Arthur Larson on Propaganda Conference, Feb. 22, 1966 (Reel B-432)
    - Interview: Dr. Thomas Gallie on the Research Triangle Computer Center, Feb. 22, 1966 (Reel B-433)
    - Research Triangle Computer Center Opening, Feb. 14, 1966, 1 sound reel: 5 inch, 1/4 inch. (Reel B-434)